<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>rgxsec void</title><link>https://rgxsec.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on rgxsec void</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.146.5</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 10:10:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgxsec.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IaC automated code security scanning via CI/CD pipeline</title><link>https://rgxsec.github.io/posts/iaccodesecscan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 10:10:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rgxsec.github.io/posts/iaccodesecscan/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="iac-automated-code-security-scanning-via-cicd-pipeline---part-1">IaC automated code security scanning via CI/CD pipeline - part 1&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I decided to create this post since I was looking to cloud in a security perspective and noticed this would be a fun thing to try and get hands-on experience in CI\CD and the magical activity of Terraforming, uh seems so cool and wizardy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="objective">Objective&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The objective is to create a &lt;strong>Terraform config file&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>insecure&lt;/strong> configs on purpose. Test code security scanning tools, such as &lt;strong>checkov&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>tfsec&lt;/strong> and then in a part 2 in the comming future, hopefully ;) time is an elusive thing, automate the process using CI\CD pipelines, something like &lt;strong>Github actions&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://rgxsec.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 13:52:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rgxsec.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="whoami">&lt;code>$whoami&lt;/code>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My name is Rui Gonçalo, I work as a Senior SOC Analyst for Kaspersky Lab. I decided to create this blog to share stuff I learned and worked on my own time. I always find that I also learn better when I&amp;rsquo;m explaining to someone else so this blog is also for me. I will write mostly about infosec areas, such as &lt;strong>Cloud, Malware, Threat Intel and Forensics&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>All information and opinions shared on this blog, are my own not my employer&lt;/strong>, as well as all text you will read is written by me, &lt;strong>I will only be using AI for task assistance&lt;/strong> such as coding and other stuff like cool images from anime or video games I played as a kid.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>